

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING STUDENT

ACHRAF FEYDI

GET IN CONTACT

Mobile: +216 52005985

faidi.Achref@insat.u-carthage.tn

GitHub

LinkedIn

Tunis, Tunisia

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a 4th year Software engineering Student with a high GPA.

I am very passionate about Problem Solving and software architecture. I have good communication, negotiation and leadership skills that I've gained during my current and past work experiences, volunteering work and competitions.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Programming Languages: C, C++, java, kotlin, Dart, JavaScript, php, SQL, python.
- Frameworks:
 - Flutter, Android Java, Android Kotlin, Xamarin.
 - SQL, MongoDB
 - REST (ExpressJs, Nest, Spring Boot), Graph-QL (Apollo GraphQL)
 - Angular, HTML/CSS, Javascript.
 - · Azure, AWS, GCP.
- Tools: GIT, JIRA, BitBucket.
- UI/UX Design.
- Machine Learning/ Deep Learning
- Testing
- DevOps

OTHER SKILLS

- · Decision making & documentation.
- · Troubleshoot & Debug Issues
- Leadership & Tasks management.
- SCRUM

WORK EXPERIENCE

ANDROID SOFTWARE ENGINEER (STUDENT JOB)

Think-it, Tunis | 09/2020 - Present

- · Working in the client's team.
 - Studying and proposing a better architecture for the App.
 - Refactoring and implementing the new Architecture
 - Fixing bugs and making the code testable (Kotlin)
 - Implementing a new Design
- Help with recruitment (Technical Tests)

PARTIME BACKEND CONSULTANT (STUDENT JOB)

ListMe, London | 08/2020 - Present

- · Planning for new features.
- Implementing new features (Apollo GraphQL, MongoDB, Firebase ...)
- Fixing Bugs

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT INTERN

Expensya, Tunis | 07/2020 - 08/2020

- Help to improve the quality of the mobile App:
 - Finding and fixing Bugs in production (Xamarin native, Xamarin forms, .NET).
 - Writing Unit Tests and E2E Tests (C#).
 - Implementing new features. Expansya's stack is based on Microsoft products, so during my internship is learned how to use many Microsoft products and Services including Azure portal, Azure DevOps, App Center, and Team Foundation Server (TFS)

MOBILE DEVELOPMENT INTERN

Orange, Tunis | 07/2019 - 10/2019

- Develop a social network app for dogs Owners (Flutter)
- Working on a smart connected kennel (Hardware + software)

EDUCATION HISTORY

NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF APPLIED SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY

- Software engineering cycle (Specialized in DevOps and Cloud)
 - Sept 2019 to Present
- Integrated preparatory cycle MPI (Maths, Physics, Informatics)
 - 2017 to June 2019

PROJECTS

2021: CRYPTO:

Description:

This project is a demonstration of some cryptography algorithms using Flutter Framework including:

- Coding/Decoding.
- Hashing / Hash cracking.
- Symmetric encryption/decryption.
- Asymmetric encryption/decryption.
- Also for fun, we implemented A Chatroom App & Messenger chat app inside the main app in order to demonstrate how Symmetric and Asymmetric encryption works.

Architecture:

- Flutter Mobile App: Git Repo
- NodeJs Backend (Socket Server + KeyServer): Git Repo
- Documentation

2021: FULLY CUSTOMIZABLE DATE RANGE PICKER PLUGIN:

Description

This is a fully customizable date range picker plugin for the Flutter framework:

- Fully Customizable with Custom Builders.
- Can Attach dynamic Data to each day.

Links

Article in Medium: <u>link</u>Plugin on pub.dev: link

2020: EVENT MANAGER:

Description:

This System would help Clubs managing their events, generating online Tickets, managing Staff and measuring attendance and participation of users.

Architecture:

- Flutter Mobile App for Staff: Git Repo
- Flutter Web Dashboard : website, Git Repo
- NodeJs Server (Hosted in heroku): Git Repo

PROJECT MANAGER AND IT DEPARTMENT LEAD (VOLUNTEERING)

- Brainstorming solutions for SDG-related problems.
- Guide a team of young developers on implementing digital solutions.

AWARDS

- World Finalist 2020 Microsoft ImagineCup EMEA Finals
 - Top 6 Teams out of 100 countries.
 - Certification, Article.
- Regional Finalist 2020 Microsoft ImagineCup EMEA Online Semifinals
 - Winner team: EMEA region
 - · Certification, Video.
- 1st place at the GYDC hackathon (Google Young Developers Congress)
 - Issuer: Issat Google Club
 - Health Oriented Android Native App.
- 1st place at the Dev Challenge (hackathon) during the The National Information Technology Day (NIT-DAY)
- 1st place at the first edition of the regional programming Olympiads in Soussa (2017)

2020: MYMEME:

Description:

Flutter based mobile app that uses AI to extract memes from my phone.

The App uses Convolutional neural network to predict if an images is a meme or not. (using TensorFlow Lite) . Google Play link .

Architecture:

• Flutter Mobile App: Git Repo

2019: I-REMEMBER:

Description:

Health oriented project dedicated for Alzheimer Patients and Care–Givers . Presentation Link.

Architecture:

- NodeJs Server (Hosted in Azure) : <u>Git Repo</u>
- Flutter Mobile App for the Patient : <u>Git Repo</u>
- Flutter Mobile App for the Care-Giver : Git Repo
- Azure Cognitive Services such as : Face Api , Text To Speech , Azure Maps ...